### KARAN POPAT

Lead Software Engineer | Associate Ecommerce Architect

Web: <a href="https://popatkaran.wordpress.com/">https://popatkaran.wordpress.com/</a>

Email: krn.ppt@gmail.com | Mo.: +49-15254907314

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Ecommerce Tech Architect with a strong background in PHP and GoLang, offering over 10 years of expertise. Demonstrates a deep passion for software engineering and a particular focus on e-commerce webshop development using popular frameworks such as Magento and Spryker. Exhibits a keen interest in acquiring knowledge and adopting new e-commerce frameworks. Skilled in utilizing GoLang to create efficient microservices that meet business needs. Committed to employing test and behavior-driven development methodologies, with proficiency in Scrum and Lean Kanban methodologies.

### **SKILLS**

- Languages & DBs: PHP, GoLang(beginner), JAVA, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- E-Commerce frameworks: Spryker, Magento 1 & 2, SAP Hybris, CommerceTools
- Testing frameworks: PHPUnit, PHPSpec, Behat, gomock, sqlmock, JUnit
- Javascript frameworks & libraries: jQuery, KnockoutJs, React(beginner), Gatsby
- Tools: Postman, Jira, Git, Slack, Trello, Pivotal Tracker
- Event streaming & message queue: Kafka, RabbitMQ
- Team Management & Leadership
- Communication with clients, teams, and across projects
- Requirement gathering and analysis

#### HOW DO I SPEND MY DAY AT WORK

- Code reviews: every morning I mostly spend some time doing the code reviews and providing constructive feedback.
- Agile ceremonies: dailies and weeklies, talking with the team to find out how the sprint is progressing, whether there are any blockers or someone needs help. Assess the overall situation and possible risks. Talking with POs and analysts to define the next set of work.
- Pairing sessions: lots of them with different teammates for doing code reviews together, helping them solve bugs, or providing support for the development of complex tasks.
- Development: I like to spend some time doing code on my own for complex tasks or tricky issues.
  Normally I work on tasks that define the processes or tools which help the team to do their work efficiently. For example, integration of a new test framework, integration of Kafka with the project, adding a profiling tool to project setup, etc.
- Extra activities on some days: conducting interviews, line management, and mentoring, handling skill assessment requests from peers

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# • Accenture GmbH | Lead Developer & Associate Architect

September 2021 – to date

- Provide training on Spryker to Backend developers
- o Provide support to solution/technical architects to provide e-commerce solutions
- o Provide support to the Business Development team to analyze e-commerce opportunities
- Develop and customize e-commerce webshops using Spryker(PHP)
- o Analyse requirements and create technical tasks
- o Implement features to meet client requirements to develop an e-commerce store
- Provide quality code by writing unit, integration, and acceptance tests
- o Participate in internal & external ceremonies

### • Inviqa Gmbh | PHP & GO Backend Engineer

December 2018 – August 2021

- Develop and customize e-commerce webshops using Spryker(PHP)
- o Implement microservices using Golang
- Analyse requirements and create technical tasks
- o Implement features to meet client requirements to develop an e-commerce store
- o Provide quality code by writing unit, integration, and acceptance tests
- o Participate in internal & external ceremonies
- o Requirement gathering and task creation if needed

#### • Krish Technolabs | Sr Software Engineer

March 2015 - November 2018

- Php backend developer (Magento, Magento 2)
- o Communicate with the client regarding project requirements and work accordingly for them.
- o Provide a solution for the web store.
- o Innovate new ideas to make a webshop user-friendly.
- Magento extension development.
- Magento third-party extension integration and modification.

## • Tatvasoft | Software Engineer:

June 2013 - March 2015

- Worked on various e-commerce features based on Magento 1 as a backend developer
- o Developed CMS webshops based on Drupal as a backend developer

#### **EDUCATION QUALIFICATION**

Gujarat Technological University | Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science)
 2009-2013

## **CERTIFICATIONS & DIGITAL BADGES**

- SPRYKER Spryker Certified Foundation Developer
- ADOBE COMMERCE Adobe Commerce Developer
- SAP HYBRIS Technical Essentials of SAP Commerce Cloud
- AWS AWS Cloud Quest: Cloud Practitioner